# Mark Gascoyne

Polyglot Software Engineer

GitHub: https://github.com/mgazza

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/markgascoyne

Stack Overflow:

https://stackoverflow.com/users/245052/mark

Web: <a href="https://www.markgascoyne.co.uk">https://www.markgascoyne.co.uk</a> Email: contact@markgascoyne.co.uk

Phone: 07951 553010

### **About Me**



As a Software Engineer with a Bachelor of Science degree (BSc Hons), I bring a wealth of knowledge and extensive experience in harnessing software technologies and design patterns. My track record demonstrates my creativity, reliability, resourcefulness, and self-motivation. I consistently offer solutions and possess the ability to find effective approaches to address any given problem.

### Skills

kubernetes golang helm flux skaffold kustomize github git circle-ci vuejs swagger rest dotnet sql-server csharp vbdotnet z-wave google-cloud docker linux cassandra entity-framework modbus scala nodejs tfs signalR redis azure aws mvc java spring jquery knockout backbone highcharts ssas soap ssis kafka confluence jira bitbucket postgresql react terraform k3s confluent-cloud graphql argocd gitlab

## Experience

### Vitrifi

Network Services Lead

Jun 2023 - Present

- Providing technical expertise to help design scalable and maintainable software architectures.
- Reviewing code submissions from team members to ensure adherence to coding standards, best practices, and quality.
- Assigning tasks and responsibilities to team members based on their skills and project requirements.
- Collaborating with product managers to create project plans, set milestones, and estimate timelines.
- Monitoring the team's progress, identifying bottlenecks, and taking corrective actions to ensure project goals are met.
- Supporting team members in their professional growth, helping them acquire new skills, and providing guidance on career paths.
- Promoting knowledge sharing within the team to foster a culture of learning and continuous improvement.
- Facilitating communication within the team, ensuring everyone is aligned on project goals and tasks.
- Representing the team in meetings with stakeholders, providing updates on project status and addressing concerns.
- Ensuring that appropriate testing processes are followed and that the software meets quality standards.
- Prioritizing and managing bug reports, collaborating with the team to resolve issues efficiently.

9/26/23, 8:19 AM Mark Gascoyne Resume

 Addressing conflicts or issues within the team, promoting a healthy and productive work environment.

- Escalating critical issues to upper management when necessary.
- Participating in the recruitment process, conducting interviews, and helping to build a strong team.
- Fostering a collaborative and inclusive team culture that encourages creativity and innovation.
- Ensuring that technical documentation is up to date and readily accessible to team members.
- Identifying potential risks to project delivery and taking proactive measures to mitigate them.
- Keeping up-to-date with industry trends and evaluating new technologies that can improve the team's efficiency and the quality of the software.
- Managing the team's budget and resources effectively, ensuring that resources are allocated optimally to meet project goals.
- Conducting performance reviews and providing constructive feedback to team members.
- Ensuring that the team follows company policies, including security and compliance standards.
- Identifying areas where processes and practices can be improved and implementing changes to enhance team productivity and software quality.

Skills aws golang kustomize argord k3s kubernetes docker gitlab

#### Gitops Consultant (Contract)

Dec 2022 - Jun 2023

- Align all DevOps teams with the unified GitOps deployment strategy.
- Work to create a unified GitOps deployment strategy for DevOps.
- Implement a unified GitOps deployment for all DevOps teams.
- Assist team members with use of unified GitOps deployments.
- Assist team members with GitOps local development environment.
- Assist team members with transition between manifest management tooling.
- Assist in creating a common shared understanding of all team's GitOps within the SRE function.

Skills aws golang kustomize argood flux k3s kubernetes docker gitlab

# Senior Go Developer (Contract)

Jun 2022 - Dec 2022

• Develop CI/CD pipelines in with Gitlab CI

• Develop CNE kubernetes operator

Skills aws golang kustomize argood flux k3s kubernetes docker gitlab

### Dae.mn/ Kultralab

Senior Software Engineer (Contract)

Skills

Jun 2021 - Jun 2022

- Delivery of infrastructure as code and declarative infrastructure maintained using gitops.
- Delivery of ci-cd pipelines.
- Refining the backlog, gathering requirements.
- Developing the supporting services.

aws postgresql golang skaffold kustomize flux kubernetes terraform k3s react graphql docker bitbucket jira confluence

### Ve Global

Software Consultant

*Jul 2020 - Jun 2021* 

- Restructuring of Ve's infrastructure and technology to save costs and create a more manageable environment.
- Introduce and setup local development using kustomise/skaffold/minikube.
- Rollout of GitOps to improve deployment pipelines.
- Training developers to develop best in class microservices.

Skills azure kubernetes skaffold kustomize vuejs kafka confluent-cloud golang docker flux

http://http/cv/

9/26/23, 8:19 AM Mark Gascoyne Resume

# Thermeon Worldwide Ltd

Software Engineer

Jan 2018 - Jul 2020

- Undertake the companies first leap into Kubernetes.
- Working with all teams to introduce agile way of working.
- Work with the EU development team in an agile methodology to produce the single signon solution hosted in kubernetes and written in golang.
- Work with the US/EU teams to develop and deliver the PCI encryption micro service hosted in kubernetes and written in golang.
- Work with development and infrastructure teams to introduce Git-Ops using Weaveworks and various other Kubernetes tech (cert-manager, external-dns, sealed-secrets).
- Produce a Horizontal Pod Autoscaler for Kubernetes which uses pod readiness rather than metrics for scaling.
- Produce client facing website for booking rentals.

Skills

github circle-ci kubernetes golang helm flux vuejs google-cloud docker linux cassandra swagger rest

### **Utilitywise PLC**

Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2015 - Jan 2018

- Development of the Wiselife IoT product
- Development of supporting services
- Development and management of data services

Skills

entity-framework sql-server z-wave modbus cassandra scala dotnet entity-framework nodejs docker linux tfs signalR redis git azure aws

### t-mac Technologies Ltd

Software Engineer

*Apr 2012 - Apr 2015* 

- Designed and developed customized energy dashboards for diverse clients, enhancing data visualization and analysis capabilities.
- Spearheaded the creation of the tmac energy analytics platform, optimizing energy consumption insights for stakeholders.
- Engineered data ingestion and processing services, streamlining data handling and analysis workflows for improved efficiency.

Skills

csharp mvc java spring jquery entity-framework knockout backbone highcharts ssas

### EnServe Group Limited

Software Engineer

Sep 2010 - Apr 2012

- Development and maintenance of Job Track Enterprise (JTE) for H2O Water Services Ltd and Thames Water /Veolia Water.
- Full involvement in maintenance and in ongoing development of the JTE system for H2O, including Smartclient application, website, web services, mobile devices database and SSIS packages.
- Full involvement in development of the JTE system for Thames Water in the run-up to live deployment, including all of the above elements plus integration with the IBM Websphere messaging system for near real-time integration with the Insight TMA system.
- Full involvement in interpretation of new requirements for both JTE systems in consultation with others both internal and external, technical and non-technical.

Skills soap csharp sql-server vbdotnet ssis

### Cse-Healthcare

http://http/cv/

9/26/23, 8:19 AM Mark Gascoyne Resume

### Systems Ltd

Student Software Engineer

Jun 2008 - Sep 2009

- Maintaining product specialist's demo laptop builds of RiO
- Development / Maintenance of internal tools used by all areas of CSE-healthcare systems
- Working as part of the live service team investigating software issues. Issuing hot fixes and releases.
- Working as part of the testing team testing software modules. Identifying code paths and testing plans.
- Design and created the replacement correspondence reference system which is used company wide (CSE-Global(UK) Ltd).
- Design and created a testing automation framework. I created a framework that automated web pages from the user point of view. I made the framework very flexible and reusable and created documentation that allowed a novice to quickly create tests and reuse code that has previously been created.

Skills csharp sql-server ssis

## Education

### Sheffield Hallam University

BSc(Hons) Software Engineering

2006 - 2010

http://http/cv/